Alaina Kafkes

Awards

Anita Borg Institute Scholar

June 2016. Won an all-expenses paid trip to the Grace Hopper Celebration for excellence in innovation & leadership.

PanHellenic Scholar

May 2016. Received a merit scholarship that honors exceptional undergraduates of Greek-American heritage.

Personal Projects

TweetFund

August 2016 – Present.

Creating a Chrome extension that facilitates donations to causes that are trending hashtags. Technologies used: JavaScript.

Myrror

January 2016 - Present.

Developed and cast a web app onto a twoway mirror in order to assess young adult body confidence using the principles of social comparison theory. Pitched proof of concept to 50+ students and professors. Currently revamping the interface with the intent of publishing a paper. Technologies used: JavaScript, JQuery, Firebase API.

Dibz

January 2016 - June 2016.

Founded and developed a web app that offers online sellers the ability to generate a bitlink to share a listing in informal, online communities. Launched to 50+ beta testers. Technologies used: JavaScript, RiotJS, Firebase API, HTML/CSS.

Rude

February 2016 (HackIllinois).

Coded Android app that encourages users to spend quality time socializing without checking their phone. Technologies used: Java, Facebook API.

Education

Northwestern University | Computer Science, Chemistry

Bachelor's Degree Anticipated June 2017. Cumulative GPA: 3.69/4.00

Work Experience

Delta Lab | iOS Engineer & UX Researcher

September 2016 – Present. Building an iOS app that helps users build habits in running and meditation while simultaneously crowdsourcing data about their surroundings. Languages used: Swift.

Clarifai | Remote Developer Evangelist

August 2016 – Present. Presented introduction to APIs lecture & Twitter Bot tutorial to 140+ viewers on YouTube Live. Will code projects that showcase the Clarifai API, host more in-person and online talks, and maintain a tech blog. Technologies used: Python, Twitter API.

GE Healthcare | Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 – August 2016. Contributed 300+ lines of code to the Media Manager web app, which expedites the binding of images & videos to patient data in a vendor-neutral archive. Spearheaded the creation of a mock server to prevent end-to-end testing with sensitive patient information. Technologies used: AngularJS 2, NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, HTML/CSS.

Northwestern University | Teaching Assistant

December 2015 – Present. Assists students in an introductory programming course through the creation of a network and with object-oriented programming questions. Languages used: C++.

Extracurriculars & Offices Held

Women in Computing | Internal President

April 2015 – Present. Established first-ever mentorship program for undergraduate & graduate women in tech, with 40+ participants in the pilot program. Organizes and teaches at weekly, campus hack nights with 100+ attendees. Founded BuildHer women's hackathon, projected for April 2017.

EPIC | Project Lead & Web Developer

April 2016 – June 2016. Built website for the Northwestern Venture Challenge. Technologies used: Sass, Gulp, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.

Peer Health Exchange | Senior Health Educator

September 2014 – June 2016. Taught the ninth grade health & sexual education curriculum at Chicago Public Schools.